<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on No Thomas</title>
    <link>//localhost:1314/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on No Thomas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>© 2024 Thomas</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="//localhost:1314/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>12/12 - A song for every month of 2024</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured_hu491a399b17041f7f8ac85ff5a772b133_346340_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured_hu491a399b17041f7f8ac85ff5a772b133_346340_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured_hu491a399b17041f7f8ac85ff5a772b133_346340_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured_hu491a399b17041f7f8ac85ff5a772b133_346340_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured_hu491a399b17041f7f8ac85ff5a772b133_346340_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;12 over 12 2024: Songs edition&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;12 over 12: 2024 Songs edition&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;12 over 12 
    &lt;div id=&#34;12-over-12&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#12-over-12&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For once in a while, I&amp;rsquo;ve grown impatient for next year. When I was a child, I cringed at the thought of New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve and realizing my end-of-year school vacations were coming to an end. This feeling endured in my late year experiences throughout my high school &amp;amp; college years; Hell, even after working as a programmer for several years, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really want the year to end. Last year I was obsessed with the idea of 2023 turning eternal; the same last week repeating &lt;em&gt;over, and over again&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; so that I could enjoy my PTO a bit longer and never have to return to the office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter half of that year had turned repetitive and there wasn&amp;rsquo;t really any highlights in my life, not much to wake up for; little motivation towards anything. This year, even though I find myself transitioning from an unhappy software engineer, to a freelance or, &amp;ldquo;en-tre-pre-neur&amp;rdquo;-ish mode of life (I hate the current connotations this word possesses); where uncertainty clouds my near-future and evokes a sense of insecurity and anxiety on me, I find myself itching for New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, impatient for what&amp;rsquo;s to come, to the point that I had the brilliant idea to summarize the feelings, sensations and experiences I had the privilege of experiencing, with a collage of twelve songs, from twelve different artists, for each of the twelve months of the year; twelve, twelve, twelve, like the amount of numbers in a traditional wall clock.. Oh well, enough rambling, as I present to &lt;strong&gt;YOU&lt;/strong&gt; my 12 over 12 songs for 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;January - Meet the Frownies - Mr. Twin Sister 
    &lt;div id=&#34;january---meet-the-frownies---mr-twin-sister&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#january---meet-the-frownies---mr-twin-sister&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/P-F7AS-Xhus?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contrary to its dreamy flirtations&lt;/strong&gt; with the &lt;em&gt;lettuce of the devil&lt;/em&gt; (a.k.a. weed) and a relationship blossoming in a friend&amp;rsquo;s yard in the song&amp;rsquo;s lyrics, the reason why January is represented by Mr. Twin Sister&amp;rsquo;s musical hit, &lt;em&gt;Meet the Frownies&lt;/em&gt;, is because of a short adventure I had during that month, as a means to escape from everything that reminded me of my old job, if only temporarily. The waves of shoe gaze blasting in the cabin of the tiny airplane that sent me flying from Juan Santamaria&amp;rsquo;s (SJO) airport, down to the miles long beaches tanning Nosara&amp;rsquo;s coast along with a troop of celebrities, strange characters, gentrifying shake ups and surf memories that carried me to a short stay in the land where locals feel like foreigners in their own land.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How could such a beautiful, hidden jewel&lt;/strong&gt; evaporate to thin air so quickly, less than 12 years from when I enjoyed the empty beaches, in the cheap, rainy season, with family and friends? My childhood memories of Nosara&amp;rsquo;s two famous beaches: Guiones and Pelada, were immediately tainted with a scenery of gringo café&amp;rsquo;s and bungalows, who desperately tried to grasp the Californian spirit from a land that they snatched away from the Tico&amp;rsquo;s at a fire sale, a fire sale the Costa Rican government encouraged, incentivized and fabricated through their lax land-leasing/land-purchasing and digital nomad regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Despite this sour image, I&lt;/strong&gt; did find myself returning (if only for one day) to my old passion: Martial arts. There was a yoga/physical conditioning bootcamp near Guiones beach, where I had the fortune of meeting a great teacher who brought back the memories of those painful days filled with excitement and lust for living. I was never good at Boxing, Muay Thai, or Taekwondo, but back then in January, the &lt;em&gt;Nalu Studio&lt;/em&gt; offered some Boxing classes, and whenever I took Boxing, I felt completely in sync and at peace with my mind and body, as if every strike, every hook, every jab, expelled those bottled up emotions I kept over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boxing wasn&amp;rsquo;t the only activity&lt;/strong&gt; during my three night stay at Nosara. I also started practicing surfing, receiving private classes with a Tico coach (Thank God). The few locals at the surf camp were shocked, mentioning to me how I was the first tico they&amp;rsquo;ve seen signing up for surfing classes, ever, and they kindly gave me the locals discount =) I spent my last afternoon at Guiones beach learning and failing at dominating the sea with my rented longboard, my rented long sleeved suit and a lovely sun blocker offered by my surf teacher. It was such a brief moment, but back then it felt nice to take on the challenge on learning how to surf, and I wish I&amp;rsquo;m able to return to the beach soon to hone my surfing skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All these moments&lt;/strong&gt;, along with my daily walks at Guiones and Pelada beach, submerging my awareness in the ocean waves clashing with the coast, bring back this dreamy pop song to my mind, as if whenever I visualize myself back there, somewhere, someone is blasting Andrea Estella&amp;rsquo;s voice (Mr. Twin Sister&amp;rsquo;s vocalist) right as I ride a rented bicycle through the golden dunes eroded by the salt water tides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;February - Give Up - Low Roar 
    &lt;div id=&#34;february---give-up---low-roar&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#february---give-up---low-roar&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iPGvMTqkUok?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;February was a month in which I&lt;/strong&gt; felt stressed over a lot of external factors. My mother needed to go under surgery for a malignant growth in her skin, and my return to work just a couple weeks prior was marked by a lot of team changes (Under my tenure at ActiveCampaign, I rotated teams at least five times), and I needed to juggle this delicate work life balance of mine, with my final french lessons (Oh la la). Low Roar has always found a way to soothe those feelings of despair that crept over my shoulders during these difficult times, its angelic voice emerging from Ryan Karazija&amp;rsquo;s lips made me feel at peace, if only for the three minute duration of this underrated jewel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ryan went on to create another&lt;/strong&gt; three dream pop albums along with his group of musicians, before tragically passing away on October 2022, from sickness. His death, along with Bowie&amp;rsquo;s passing are some of the events that have left a grueling impact in me, and millions of fans around the world, I&amp;rsquo;m sure of that&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;March - Tio Minuter - Parson Sound 
    &lt;div id=&#34;march---tio-minuter---parson-sound&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#march---tio-minuter---parson-sound&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Vco5W_wqYhU?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water shortages in Costa Rica&lt;/strong&gt; had already been around for most of February, and would stay here until late June. These water shortages went on for at least three days per week, from 7am to 7pm. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to picture a world without such a basic necessity, and yet many people around the globe constantly drown in the quest to satiate their thirst. My outlook for Costa Rica looked quite bleak; Uncertainty, social disorder and a petri dish of crises droning around my head, &lt;strong&gt;Tio Minuter&lt;/strong&gt;, from the now defunct Nordic psychedelic rock band, &lt;em&gt;Pärson Sound&lt;/em&gt;, was the etiquette I thought about for this month, marking a period of constant anguish that&amp;rsquo;s well identified with the loud horns and electrical drones buzzing in the ears of the listeners of &lt;strong&gt;Tio Minuter&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;April - Nevermind the Living Dead - Stuck in the Sound 
    &lt;div id=&#34;april---nevermind-the-living-dead---stuck-in-the-sound&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#april---nevermind-the-living-dead---stuck-in-the-sound&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/OhjYy229YHg?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I was never a big fan of Stuck in the Sound&lt;/strong&gt;. During April, I was contacted by several companies, offering me the chance to apply to a niche of full-stack developer openings. Most of the time, I was assigned some take home assignments, and I listened to &lt;strong&gt;Nevermind the Living Dead&lt;/strong&gt;, the album of the French rock group &lt;em&gt;Stuck in the Sound&lt;/em&gt; (SITS). The homologous track of the album, made me remember the times me and some childhood friends would play around the neighborhood, during the late 2000s and early 2010s. It made me wonder if those days were truly gone.. how could they be gone so quickly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;That was until late April&lt;/strong&gt;, when Erick (another childhood friend) and I received the devastating news from another childhood friend, Emmanuel: His beloved grandmother (who our family was very close with) had just passed away, a couple days prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Erick and I were there at the funeral&lt;/strong&gt;, not only to respect her memory, but also to uplift our friend&amp;rsquo;s spirits (At the time, Emmanuel lived in the US, while his grandma lived here in CR). &lt;strong&gt;Nevermind the Living Dead&lt;/strong&gt; is a song that I can identify with this month, despite the singer&amp;rsquo;s broken English in this song, the melodies made me remember how quickly time goes by, and how important it is to cherish those around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;May - Feelings (Blind Digital Citizen Remix) - Concorde 
    &lt;div id=&#34;may---feelings-blind-digital-citizen-remix---concorde&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#may---feelings-blind-digital-citizen-remix---concorde&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/68rU7W6nR-M?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May was my last month together with my old french class!&lt;/strong&gt; It was also the month that culminated with my graduation from the 10th (and final) french level in the French Alliance. We threw a big party at a local celebrity&amp;rsquo;s apartment, who I had the privilege of being classmates with for three whole levels (gracias Nancy!). May is also my birthday month! and since I reached the ripe age 24, I went to a local italian restaurant with my family so that I could enjoy some tasty pizza. The mood around the time was nostalgic, dense, uncertain, like those feelings evoked from the &lt;em&gt;Blind Digital Citizen&lt;/em&gt; remix of &lt;em&gt;Concorde&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rsquo;s track, &lt;strong&gt;Feelings&lt;/strong&gt;. Also, that month I used to drive early in the mornings to my swimming classes (6 AM) and I would play this song along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;June - Spoon - Cibo Matto 
    &lt;div id=&#34;june---spoon---cibo-matto&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#june---spoon---cibo-matto&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/oveep8Rt8RA?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s funny how I mentioned Italian cuisine&lt;/strong&gt; in the previous month, while saving the Italian sounding group name &lt;em&gt;Cibo Matto&lt;/em&gt; for june (and no, &lt;em&gt;Cibo Matto&lt;/em&gt; is NOT an Italian music band). My interviews at a certain company, turned south at the very end, and I soon found myself having wasted more than 4 hours within &lt;strong&gt;9 different interviews&lt;/strong&gt;. To throw some more salt to the wound, I was rejected a promotion by my boss that same month and I caught some awful cold that ruined my immune system for the latter half of June; the stress of my job and me preparing everything for all these job interviews, taxed my body spectacularly. June had a very accelerated, frenetic mood, and Cibo Matto&amp;rsquo;s song &lt;strong&gt;Spoon&lt;/strong&gt; upbeat yet hyperactive tone reflects this accurately. A month of failures that went by quickly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;July - Generator - Justice 
    &lt;div id=&#34;july---generator---justice&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#july---generator---justice&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/ZX83_kg_n5c?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Olympics&lt;/strong&gt;, my favorite time of the &lt;em&gt;Olympiad&lt;/em&gt; period (an Olympiad is a four-year period from the previous Olympics ceremony until the next). Justice was the main protagonist in July&amp;rsquo;s musical scene, especially considering their newly released album, &lt;strong&gt;HYPERDRAMA&lt;/strong&gt;, just a couple months back. July&amp;rsquo;s song, &lt;strong&gt;Generator&lt;/strong&gt;, was a breathe of fresh air. For me, this song is very intoxicating, rebellious, and I found it fitting when it played at the closing ceremony of the Paris 2024 Summer Olympics: The crowd echoing their cheers across the stadium, as the Olympic athletes parade triumphantly around the arena, showing pride in their achievements, something from these whole setting made me wish I was there, part of the Olympian army - a vague daydream emerging from a monotone lifestyle lacking of passion and meaning&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;August - Sunday Morning - The Velvet Underground &amp;amp; Nico 
    &lt;div id=&#34;august---sunday-morning---the-velvet-underground--nico&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#august---sunday-morning---the-velvet-underground--nico&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3vnRUp9qVZ0?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The last Monday of August&lt;/strong&gt;, I had to drive myself to the SJO airport. Four years ago, I made a promise to my old friend Emilio, who was now living in Japan at the time, and I was just about to fulfill it. Monday August 30th marked my first solo intercontinental trip; From Costa Rica to Japan. During these last days of the month, I binged The Velvet Underground&amp;rsquo;s first album. &lt;em&gt;Peel Slowly and See&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s front-cover phrase always caught my attention, Warhol was a funny man indeed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Even though I left on Monday&lt;/strong&gt;, I wanted to spend my last weekend as peaceful as possible. Who knows, it could&amp;rsquo;ve been my last, had the plane taken a deadly turn, and if I was going to die that day, then I wanted to eat some pizza, hang out with some friends, return home and tune in loop the famous Velvet Underground song, &lt;strong&gt;Sunday Morning&lt;/strong&gt;. It sounded so fresh, so dreamy, as if I was transported back to childhood where I would roam around a giant supermarket&amp;rsquo;s aisles, curious of the world around me, of the colourful products and aromas that governed the grocery store, or as if it transported me back to those early days in kindergarten, our lives unbothered by the rat race, and instead I found myself playing in the greeneries surrounding the playgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;September - THAT&amp;rsquo;S THE SOUND - EMILIO 
    &lt;div id=&#34;september---thats-the-sound---emilio&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#september---thats-the-sound---emilio&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-explanatory&lt;/strong&gt;. I spent most of September in Japan, surrounded by its Shinto shrines, Royal castles, natural landscapes and neon bathed metropolis. I was there to fulfill a promise; To visit my friend, Emilio, and to assist one of its techno concerts. If you&amp;rsquo;d like to read more about how that went, you can check out the following article:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;section class=&#34;space-y-10 w-full&#34;&gt;
    
    
        
            






















  &lt;a class=&#34;flex flex-wrap article &#34; href=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/&#34;&gt;
    
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;w-full md:w-auto h-full thumbnail nozoom thumbnailshadow md:mr-7&#34; style=&#34;background-image:url(/posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_600x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg);&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
        
      &lt;div class=&#34; mt-3 md:mt-0&#34;&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;items-center text-left text-xl font-semibold&#34;&gt;
        
        &lt;div class=&#34;font-bold text-xl text-neutral-800 decoration-primary-500 hover:underline hover:underline-offset-2 dark:text-neutral&#34;
          href=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/&#34;&gt;Japan Trip: DJ. Underground Scene, Electronic Music Experience in Tokyo&lt;/div&gt;
        
        
        
      &lt;/div&gt;
      &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm text-neutral-500 dark:text-neutral-400&#34;&gt;
        











  





  



  



  



  









&lt;div class=&#34;flex flex-row flex-wrap items-center&#34;&gt;
  
  
  &lt;time datetime=&#34;2024-11-18 00:00:00 &amp;#43;0000 UTC&#34;&gt;18 November 2024&lt;/time&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;px-2 text-primary-500&#34;&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2267 words&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;px-2 text-primary-500&#34;&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span title=&#34;Reading time&#34;&gt;11 mins&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;px-2 text-primary-500&#34;&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
    
    &lt;span id=&#34;views_posts/japan-trip-special/index.md&#34; 
    
        class=&#34;animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400&#34; title=&#34;views&#34;&gt;loading&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block align-text-bottom&#34;&gt;

  &lt;span class=&#34;relative block icon&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 576 512&#34;&gt;
&lt;path fill=&#34;currentColor&#34; d=&#34;M288 32c-80.8 0-145.5 36.8-192.6 80.6C48.6 156 17.3 208 2.5 243.7c-3.3 7.9-3.3 16.7 0 24.6C17.3 304 48.6 356 95.4 399.4C142.5 443.2 207.2 480 288 480s145.5-36.8 192.6-80.6c46.8-43.5 78.1-95.4 93-131.1c3.3-7.9 3.3-16.7 0-24.6c-14.9-35.7-46.2-87.7-93-131.1C433.5 68.8 368.8 32 288 32zM432 256c0 79.5-64.5 144-144 144s-144-64.5-144-144s64.5-144 144-144s144 64.5 144 144zM288 192c0 35.3-28.7 64-64 64c-11.5 0-22.3-3-31.6-8.4c-.2 2.8-.4 5.5-.4 8.4c0 53 43 96 96 96s96-43 96-96s-43-96-96-96c-2.8 0-5.6 .1-8.4 .4c5.3 9.3 8.4 20.1 8.4 31.6z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;px-2 text-primary-500&#34;&gt;&amp;middot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;
    
    &lt;span id=&#34;likes_posts/japan-trip-special/index.md&#34; 
    
        class=&#34;animate-pulse inline-block text-transparent max-h-3 rounded-full mt-[-2px] align-middle bg-neutral-300 dark:bg-neutral-400&#34; title=&#34;likes&#34;&gt;loading&lt;/span&gt; 
    &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block align-text-bottom&#34;&gt;

  &lt;span class=&#34;relative block icon&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 512 512&#34;&gt;
&lt;path fill=&#34;currentColor&#34; d=&#34;M47.6 300.4L228.3 469.1c7.5 7 17.4 10.9 27.7 10.9s20.2-3.9 27.7-10.9L464.4 300.4c30.4-28.3 47.6-68 47.6-109.5v-5.8c0-69.9-50.5-129.5-119.4-141C347 36.5 300.6 51.4 268 84L256 96 244 84c-32.6-32.6-79-47.5-124.6-39.9C50.5 55.6 0 115.2 0 185.1v5.8c0 41.5 17.2 81.2 47.6 109.5z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  

  
  
&lt;/div&gt;







      &lt;/div&gt;
      
      &lt;div class=&#34;py-1 max-w-fit prose dark:prose-invert&#34;&gt;
        The beauty of underground techno concerts in Japan coupled with the rise of a new generation of artists, is definitely a sight worth seeing inside the club Asia bar in Shibuya
      &lt;/div&gt;
      
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
        
    
&lt;/section&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And obviously&lt;/strong&gt;, I dedicated this month to his new song: &lt;a href=&#34;https://soundcloud.com/brutalism_x_basseht/emilio-that-s-the-sound&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    THAT&amp;rsquo;S THE SOUND (Original Mix)&lt;/a&gt;. An energetic techno piece that complemented my endless supply of adventures in the land of the rising sun. This will be the only song in the blog entry that&amp;rsquo;s without a YouTube embed, but fear not, SoundCloud hosts this techno track, and if I find a way to integrate SoundCloud as a short code in the blog, then I&amp;rsquo;ll update the blog entry so that it&amp;rsquo;s easier to listen to &lt;em&gt;DJ EMILIO&lt;/em&gt; SoundCloud track =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;October - Some Are - David Bowie 
    &lt;div id=&#34;october---some-are---david-bowie&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#october---some-are---david-bowie&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fuPcbPaME5w?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It seems as if I was absorbed completely&lt;/strong&gt;, into a different reality just a month prior, in which I was ecstatic and full of energy. And now, heavy rain covered the distance whenever I looked outside, the drumming of droplets muffled all joy out of my self, as I found myself trapped at my breaking point:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A daily grind that had sucked my soul away&lt;/strong&gt;; A solitude that bathed me with each day that passed; And a country which suffocated me with stray bullets and socio-cultural desolation. My body yearned for adventure, for a way out of this place, but I found none of it, no thrill that made my heart skip, no trip to please the impatient mind that was ruminating on what to do next, as it was clear I had reached my limit at my previous job and soon after, took a leap of faith, by quitting and embracing this blog fully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Some Are&lt;/strong&gt; - the unreleased track of Bowie&amp;rsquo;s first Berlin Trilogy album: &lt;strong&gt;Low&lt;/strong&gt;, captured these feelings, with its wolves crying from the distance, the single piano note from the ouverture dangling in preparation of the now-sober Starman whispering its lyrics. &lt;em&gt;Some are bound to fail, summer winter some&amp;hellip; are&lt;/em&gt; - Bowie modulated in a wave of murmurs and sighed expressions; His exhaustion paralleled mine during this time; spiritually, mentally and physically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;During those rainy days&lt;/strong&gt;, I would mirror from under my eyelids, a pale white scenario in which my body sunk at the snow, now burgundy tainted from the open injuries across my physique, and then I&amp;rsquo;d force myself to climb the tundra in front of me, with my broken sleigh, as the wolves howled from a distance, spotting its next prey&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;November - Ay no puedo - The Marias 
    &lt;div id=&#34;november---ay-no-puedo---the-marias&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#november---ay-no-puedo---the-marias&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/y9NPx6NDA6M?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Suffered some form of heartbreak&lt;/strong&gt; at any point of your life? It&amp;rsquo;s ok, so did I, and so did &lt;strong&gt;Maria Zardoya&lt;/strong&gt;, the lead singer of the Puerto-Rican/American music group, &lt;em&gt;The Marias&lt;/em&gt;. Her new album (&lt;strong&gt;Submarine&lt;/strong&gt;) with her music group, steers away from the usual lovey-dovey, cinematic intensity of its predecessors without abandoning the psychedelic, latino-pop roots that characterized their early shows from the last decade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Submarine&lt;/strong&gt; is a blue masterpiece, dwelling on the pain of letting someone else go, something us humans must deal with during love ruptures, while battling the efforts of the subconscious mind, constantly reminding us of the &lt;em&gt;What If&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/em&gt; from a has-been relationship shattered to pieces. &lt;strong&gt;Ay no puedo&lt;/strong&gt; is a song that treats the dazzle that burns holes through the hearts of many, after a romance goes wrong. November fits this theme accurately for me at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;December - Jak III Credits Pt.2 - Josh Mancell &amp;amp; Larry Hopkins 
    &lt;div id=&#34;december---jak-iii-credits-pt2---josh-mancell--larry-hopkins&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#december---jak-iii-credits-pt2---josh-mancell--larry-hopkins&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/u8pw5izm2qA?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Last but not least&lt;/strong&gt;, December. This month, usually nostalgic for your dear author, usually glum too, was actually more upbeat than in previous years. The mood reminded me of a video game I used to play on circa 20 years ago in my PS2. &lt;em&gt;Jak III&lt;/em&gt; was the zenith of my all-time favorite video game franchise &lt;em&gt;Jak &amp;amp; Daxter&lt;/em&gt;, and it went out grandiosely after you beat the final boss (Cyber-Errol and the Dark Makers) in the Wasteland, in order to redeem the betrayed protagonist and save the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The first part of the credits&lt;/strong&gt; features a triumphant orchestra, congratulating the player for beating the game and completing the last adventure in the trilogy, but it&amp;rsquo;s really the second part of the credit&amp;rsquo;s theme composed by Josh Mancell &amp;amp; Larry Hopkins, that seals the deal for me. It offers a stark contrast to the champion&amp;rsquo;s instrumental of the first half, by laying down a sense of certainty and excitement for what&amp;rsquo;s to come, now that the war is finally over, a glimpse to the next generation, to the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The crescendos, the melodies and the soothing expansion of sounds&lt;/strong&gt;, it all sounds as if you were getting comforted by an invisible hand, telling you that no matter what&amp;rsquo;s to come, you are not alone, and everything is going to be alright..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/12-over-12-songs-2024/featured.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Trip: DJ. Underground Scene, Electronic Music Experience in Tokyo</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/featured_hu90ecfa47f4a47c9dfd94df44cf80dcce_2799894_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Club Asia Entry&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Club Asia&amp;rsquo;s entry from the outside. A multitude gathers to experience the NEBULA X DIMENSION techno music event.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Prelude 
    &lt;div id=&#34;prelude&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#prelude&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I wrote some entries to the blog. Life got in the way and I needed to rewrite this whole entry, after re-reading it, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t look too good now. The memories of the night at the NEBULA&amp;rsquo;s event remain crystal clear in my mind, however, and I wanted to give a more personal perspective on how a great techno event developed on the night of September 15th, inside the &lt;em&gt;club Asia&lt;/em&gt; venue in Shibuya. But first, an abridged summary on the advent of all music tracks that were going to be produced from that moment forward, through an army of digital instruments, at the fingertips of the artists, or in other words, the rise of &lt;strong&gt;Electronic Music&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Once upon a time 
    &lt;div id=&#34;once-upon-a-time&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#once-upon-a-time&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the late 60s Jamaica produced a new genre, a blend of existing sounds in music, manipulated so that the rhythm becomes the foundation of multiple layers of reverb, echo and other musical add-ons, became known as &lt;em&gt;dub music&lt;/em&gt;. It was an accident, where sound engineer Byron Smith, working at Duke Reid&amp;rsquo;s studio, removed the vocals for the song &amp;ldquo;On the Beach&amp;rdquo;, from the Paragons. Back then, sound operator &amp;ldquo;Ruddy&amp;rdquo; Redwood decided to keep the result as it is and play it at his next dancing event. There&amp;rsquo;s more to the story of Jamaica&amp;rsquo;s outputting of dub music, including where music pioneer Lee &amp;ldquo;Scratch&amp;rdquo; Perry played a central role in promoting it with his records. It&amp;rsquo;s incredible to think the world was moving at haste pace towards music created solely by digital instruments living inside the machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s more amusing, is the inception of machines able to reproduce sounds rapidly proliferating all across the globe, in an independent manner: During the interwar period and during World War II, the USSR, the United States, and Japan were already developing the first electro-musical instruments; Harps, organs and theremins were digitalized and their sounds exposed through recorders; Australia contributed to this technological breakthrough by launching the &lt;em&gt;CSIRAC&lt;/em&gt; computer in the early 50s, the very first machine that was able to play music. However, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the launch of the &lt;em&gt;&amp;ldquo;Ferranti Mark 1&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; computer, that humanity was able to record the first computer generated music tracks. Japan, also played a key-role in shaping the arena for electronic music with the development of the &lt;em&gt;Yamaha Magna Organ&lt;/em&gt; in 1935. But again, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until the 60s when the idea of dwelling into computer generated sounds reached a much wider, daring audience.&lt;/p&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/iS3dIyHpAgc?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1969 while conducting an interview for the Rolling Stones, famous poet Jim Morrison went on to predict the rise of solo minds tinkering with digital audio software that served &amp;ldquo;like an extension to the Moog Synthetizer, but with the richness of a whole orchestra&amp;rdquo;. Electronic music already existed way before Morrison expressed his thoughts during this interview, what matters here is the execution that was unheard of from the days of the Lizard King.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/influences_hub57a26cfd1314e89052da084010695d7_573281_330x0_resize_box_3.png 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/influences_hub57a26cfd1314e89052da084010695d7_573281_660x0_resize_box_3.png 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/influences_hub57a26cfd1314e89052da084010695d7_573281_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/influences_hub57a26cfd1314e89052da084010695d7_573281_1320x0_resize_box_3.png 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/influences_hub57a26cfd1314e89052da084010695d7_573281_660x0_resize_box_3.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;electronic music influences&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Some influences that definitely contributed to the development of electronic music. From left to right (clockwise): Kraftwerk, NEU!, Silver Apples, Skrillex&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;From Kraftwerk and NEU! to Silver Apples and Skrillex 
    &lt;div id=&#34;from-kraftwerk-and-neu-to-silver-apples-and-skrillex&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#from-kraftwerk-and-neu-to-silver-apples-and-skrillex&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Germany, the electronic music ecosystem was beginning to expand aggressively with the rise of Kraftwerk. Kraftwerk leveraged a lot of electronic sounds with synthetizers to create their own brand of music. Years later, their descendant, NEU!, would go even further with the conceptualization of remixes in the form of slowed-down/sped-up variations of their songs, this is evident in their second album, &lt;em&gt;NEU! 2&lt;/em&gt; where they decided to release alternate versions of &lt;em&gt;Super&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Neuschnee&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Groups like Stereolab also made use of synthesizers through many of their albums in order to achieve an &lt;em&gt;avant-garde&lt;/em&gt; set of tunes, seen in their &lt;em&gt;Dots and Loops&lt;/em&gt; album. Ironically, Stereolab was influenced by &lt;em&gt;Silver Apples&lt;/em&gt;, the American electronic music group. Still, these were not the groups that Morrison predicted in his interview, I believe he would&amp;rsquo;ve been pleased to know that his prediction manifested decades later, with the advent of Skrillex, and DJs, the latter working in their own dubs in a solo manner. I also believe that many DJs took inspiration in at least one of the sources I previously mentioned.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The French Touch (90s-00s) 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-french-touch-90s-00s&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#the-french-touch-90s-00s&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The French house scene, serves as a prime example of what happens when youth is allowed to expand on existing foundations, by adding fringe elements to the pitch. Even though they started with little recognition and deviating from the original Euro disco strand floating around the old continent during the 80s, they were able to revolutionize and quickly grow their &lt;em&gt;repertoire&lt;/em&gt;, attracting millions of fans around the world throughout the process. &lt;em&gt;Air&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Daft Punk&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Justice&lt;/em&gt; are some of the groups that came from this era and they all shared humble origins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Justice started by creating remixes from &lt;em&gt;Microloisir&lt;/em&gt; in 2003 and rapidly became a powerhouse once their debut album &amp;ldquo;†&amp;rdquo; came to be less than 4 years after their initial track compilation. They&amp;rsquo;re a personal favorite of mine due to the fact that &amp;ldquo;†&amp;rdquo; was produced with a lot of samples from Apple&amp;rsquo;s sample library and putting them together in Garageband. Obviously this is a gross oversimplification of what they did, but it shows to aspiring electronic music creators how little to no resources, are not a constraint for creativity, in fact, we could say constraints force creativity to the surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The Tokyo Electronic Scene 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-tokyo-electronic-scene&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#the-tokyo-electronic-scene&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/club_asia_anniversary_hu4098fa847ca2342c620fba1f86ee9d83_98921_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/club_asia_anniversary_hu4098fa847ca2342c620fba1f86ee9d83_98921_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/club_asia_anniversary_hu4098fa847ca2342c620fba1f86ee9d83_98921_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/club_asia_anniversary_hu4098fa847ca2342c620fba1f86ee9d83_98921_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/club_asia_anniversary_hu4098fa847ca2342c620fba1f86ee9d83_98921_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Club Asia anniversary&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Club Asia&amp;rsquo;s 28th Anniversary!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just in Tokyo, there are over 29 upcoming electronic music events, just for this month alone. There&amp;rsquo;s also a knack of bars around prefectures such as: Nakano (CLUB PRIMERA, MELODIA), Shibuya (WOMB, club asia), Shinjuku (SPACE) and Minato (VENT), each of them with their own charm, and many more. The Electronic music scene (underground, techno, hard-techno, house, etc) in the Eastern Capital continues to grow as the amount of tourists increases each year, giving a multicultural population to the bars in the region. For this blog entry, &lt;em&gt;club asia&lt;/em&gt; was used as a documentary place, since this is where the main event of this post was held.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently, &lt;em&gt;club asia&lt;/em&gt; was on its 28th anniversary by the time I went to the entrance lounge. Inside, it sports a very spacious yet unconventional structure, for example, in the entrance lounge, performers stand at the very center of the bar - that&amp;rsquo;s their stage for them to do their magic - instead of remaining at the very back of the bar. There&amp;rsquo;s a second floor with another stage which is a bit more traditional and then on the east wing of the bar there&amp;rsquo;s the massive concert area where the other DJs played too, sporting a wide screen covering the back walls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/center_huefe56f03a267da0d9691f7e8877cc0e2_569387_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/center_huefe56f03a267da0d9691f7e8877cc0e2_569387_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/center_huefe56f03a267da0d9691f7e8877cc0e2_569387_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/center_huefe56f03a267da0d9691f7e8877cc0e2_569387_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/center_huefe56f03a267da0d9691f7e8877cc0e2_569387_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Club Asia main (entrance/center) longue&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;club asia&amp;rsquo;s entrance lounge&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The decorations there are very lovely and security is kind enough to let you in even as a foreigner. I was a bit worried about my choice of clothes, an oversized t-shirt, colorful shorts and shoes, practically the worst combination for these sort of events, but security does not enforce a dress code, which was good for me. Speaking of security, it is obvious to say that you cannot bring drinks inside the bar and no people under 20 years old are allowed during clubbing hours. More than obvious, as a foreigner, you should bring your passport as your identification (and also to avoid any problems with the police)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Featured Bio: DJ Emilio (Miguel Emilio Marin Orias) 
    &lt;div id=&#34;featured-bio-dj-emilio-miguel-emilio-marin-orias&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#featured-bio-dj-emilio-miguel-emilio-marin-orias&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd_hua57948b7627eb3094fea443d1e77048c_600234_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd_hua57948b7627eb3094fea443d1e77048c_600234_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd_hua57948b7627eb3094fea443d1e77048c_600234_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd_hua57948b7627eb3094fea443d1e77048c_600234_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd_hua57948b7627eb3094fea443d1e77048c_600234_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;DJ Emilio&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;DJ Emilio. An emerging techno music producer and event organizer, from Costa Rica, performing in front of his followers, as part of his NEBULA X DIMENSION event&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Emilio (Miguel)&lt;/strong&gt; was born on November 28th, 1999. He lived most of his life in Costa Rica, where I had the privilege to meet him during our middle school years, and soon after became friends. After graduating from high school, he worked at sales commissions in Sykes in order to save enough money to emigrate from Costa Rica. As he always mentioned, he was looking for a place in which he&amp;rsquo;d be able to fit in perfectly with a like-minded group of people, which he believed were not necessarily there in his (our) country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Emilio always sported a bold mindset towards chasing his dreams, something that has deeply inspired me and I&amp;rsquo;m sure has inspired many others along the way. By the end of 2019, he was able to sign up for Japanese language classes and was given the opportunity to study Japanese at the Shinjuku Japanese Language Institute - SNG. After the COVID shutdowns - which delayed his departure for a short while - Emilio immigrated to &amp;ldquo;The Land of the Sun&amp;rdquo; on October 2020. He&amp;rsquo;s long since established himself there as a DJ and event organizer while also studying to pursue a career in marketing and fashion at the Professional Institute of International Fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/miguel_hufb5fa2a15af3fa8ec228faeb94436b78_272375_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/miguel_hufb5fa2a15af3fa8ec228faeb94436b78_272375_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/miguel_hufb5fa2a15af3fa8ec228faeb94436b78_272375_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/miguel_hufb5fa2a15af3fa8ec228faeb94436b78_272375_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/miguel_hufb5fa2a15af3fa8ec228faeb94436b78_272375_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpg&#34;
        alt=&#34;DJ Emilio 2&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;DJ Emilio. Pic taken from picuki (his instagram -&amp;gt; @emilio_marin99)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His efforts now pay off, being the founder of the NEBULA Event Planner group, and growing to become a recognized DJ and event organizer himself. His path has not been easy, but he&amp;rsquo;s been able to adapt himself and learn rapidly to overcome all obstacles in his way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Inside the NEBULA X DIMENSION event 
    &lt;div id=&#34;inside-the-nebula-x-dimension-event&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#inside-the-nebula-x-dimension-event&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/flyer_hu16ef9ac6d0b20fae9a617e9ee1d2bade_1668056_330x0_resize_box_3.png 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/flyer_hu16ef9ac6d0b20fae9a617e9ee1d2bade_1668056_660x0_resize_box_3.png 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/flyer_hu16ef9ac6d0b20fae9a617e9ee1d2bade_1668056_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/flyer_hu16ef9ac6d0b20fae9a617e9ee1d2bade_1668056_1320x0_resize_box_3.png 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/flyer_hu16ef9ac6d0b20fae9a617e9ee1d2bade_1668056_660x0_resize_box_3.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;NEBULA X DIMENSION FLYER&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A flyer promoting the NEBULA X DIMENSION collab event&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Performance 
    &lt;div id=&#34;performance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#performance&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The event was organized by tico (Costa Rican) DJ Emilio, together with a variety of techno artists situated in Japan. Emilio, who moved to Japan more than four years ago to pursue an education in the Japanese language, and subsequently went on to study fashion at the Professional Fashion Institute in Shinjuku, Tokyo, found himself experimenting with sounds through an used synth he acquired back in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From there, he soon found himself participating in local techno venues around Japan, and was now hosting one of the largest events around Shibuya in the &lt;em&gt;club asia&lt;/em&gt; bar, connecting a very diverse demography of electronic music fans, in an arena that could fit multiple DJs simultaneously, in different chambers; Each chamber represented a different world and its sounds did not leak into the other universes. All artists played concurrently at the different stages of the bar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd2_huacd1aae75b9f2ab21c6d8d124e71d06c_622036_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd2_huacd1aae75b9f2ab21c6d8d124e71d06c_622036_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd2_huacd1aae75b9f2ab21c6d8d124e71d06c_622036_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd2_huacd1aae75b9f2ab21c6d8d124e71d06c_622036_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/emilio_crowd2_huacd1aae75b9f2ab21c6d8d124e71d06c_622036_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Another view of the crowd&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Another view of the crowd.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Diversity in attendance 
    &lt;div id=&#34;diversity-in-attendance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#diversity-in-attendance&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immense cheers and a sense of ecstasy echoed through the walls and the energy from the wild encapsulated what I remember as a very diverse sub-culture, of hard techno-fans jumping and dancing around the &lt;em&gt;tempos&lt;/em&gt; of these talented musical artists. In a single night, you could hear a dozen different dialects, a cluster of languages that converged into a single meaning; Love for the spectacle unraveling in front of hundreds of attendees:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;French, Spanish, Italian, German, English, Japanese were some of the languages I overheard as I was frantically filming the concert and grabbing takes for this blog entry, from a staircase that struggling with supporting my weight and the weight of a couple more fans in the stage. Ethnically speaking, you could spin your head around and find yourself surrounded by people from all the five continents on Earth, what an incredible spectacle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Struggles 
    &lt;div id=&#34;struggles&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#struggles&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the concert was incredibly well organized, a shared problematic currently hovers over the artists shoulder&amp;rsquo;s, an off-key note that could potentially deafen both the artists and attendees expectations if left unsupervised. &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s the lack of support from local venues, to help emerging artists thrive&amp;rdquo; - Emilio mentioned to me in one of our many discussions concerning the difficulties DJ&amp;rsquo;s like him face once they try to organize an event such as &lt;em&gt;NEBULA X DIMENSION&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sad truth is, logistics, supply chains, strategic locations, all of these responsibilities accrue on the artists, on top of all the track mixing and musical preparations they need to work on, ahead of the big event itself. Promoting these events and giving them enough visibility, is also a pain point that many aspiring electronic music performers have to face nowadays, as mainstream social media such as Instagram, or event organizing apps such as Meetup, don&amp;rsquo;t put them in the spotlight most of the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The printing and development of t-shirts, and all its logistics falls also in the organizer&amp;rsquo;s shoulders where they can face many setbacks and misunderstandings. There&amp;rsquo;s plenty of opportunity for inventors and creative minds to try and resolve these issues to empower local artists, but unfortunately for now, many artists like Emilio continue to experience these struggles every time they organize a new music festival.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The next generation of electronic artists 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-next-generation-of-electronic-artists&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#the-next-generation-of-electronic-artists&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the next generation of electronic (music) artists, there are a lot of existing challenges that might make it a bit difficult to start in the live performance universe. However, I&amp;rsquo;m growing more convinced by the day that other leaders, entrepreneurs or innovative souls will bring their worries to a halt and actually improve the logistics and organization capabilities very soon. Who knows, perhaps we will see an integration of events, merchandise and supply chains in a distributed manner, with a solid UI/UX experience so that artists are empowered to create their own events while receiving automated assistance from venues, merch makers, sound system providers, etc. I&amp;rsquo;m very confident &amp;amp; excited on what the future holds for those creative minds that will be inspired by what collaborative events such as the NEBULA X DIMENSION have achieved, with so little budget albeit an enormous amount of perseverance and boldness to experiment with new streams of raw, powerful sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;SOCIALS &amp;amp; CONTACTS 
    &lt;div id=&#34;socials--contacts&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#socials--contacts&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DJ Emilio INSTAGRAM: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/emilio_marin99/?utm_source=qr&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    https://www.instagram.com/emilio_marin99/?utm_source=qr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEBULA YOUTUBE CHANNEL: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/@Nebula-j6t&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    https://www.youtube.com/@Nebula-j6t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NEBULA INSTAGRAM: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/nebula.tokyo/?utm_source=qr&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    https://www.instagram.com/nebula.tokyo/?utm_source=qr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-special/featured.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Trip: Arriving at Osaka, Castle, Nightlife Shinkansen Experience</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Crumbling feet 
    &lt;div id=&#34;crumbling-feet&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#crumbling-feet&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured_hue6dc216b71f4a3714bc71adaba08caa1_111252_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured_hue6dc216b71f4a3714bc71adaba08caa1_111252_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured_hue6dc216b71f4a3714bc71adaba08caa1_111252_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured_hue6dc216b71f4a3714bc71adaba08caa1_111252_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured_hue6dc216b71f4a3714bc71adaba08caa1_111252_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Osaka Nightlife&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A glimpse of Osaka&amp;rsquo;s nightlife in the Shinsaibashisuji district&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This entry will be rather short. Originally I had plans to expand more on Osaka&amp;rsquo;s famous attractions, such as the &lt;em&gt;Tsutenkaku&lt;/em&gt;, but I had an unfortunate incident in the afternoon after my trip to the Osaka Castle. I was extremely sweaty from walking tens of thousands of footsteps across Osaka, disorganized from the sun showering the city with its golden heat, forming a tepid atmosphere like no other. My home country isn&amp;rsquo;t as humid or as warm as Osaka, changing weathers then, wasn&amp;rsquo;t going to work to my benefit, along with long walking distances to go from one place to another, something that Japan is famous for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts_hu65da044ceb22b9aacef62befaaa8b417_297837_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts_hu65da044ceb22b9aacef62befaaa8b417_297837_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts_hu65da044ceb22b9aacef62befaaa8b417_297837_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts_hu65da044ceb22b9aacef62befaaa8b417_297837_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts_hu65da044ceb22b9aacef62befaaa8b417_297837_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Osaka Castle Outskirts&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Outskirts of the famous Osaka Castle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Castle 
    &lt;div id=&#34;castle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#castle&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some good 40 minutes of walking, I finally arrived at the outskirts of the Osaka castle. From the outskirts, you can appreciate the fortress, the aquatic trench reflecting the sun rays and hosting a variety of submarine guards patrolling the perimeter looking (a.k.a fish). To access the castle, walking all the way through the gravy road and then pass the bridge where the aquatic friends live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts2_hu5c8dc8009c93cbd020787dde3983cb07_297543_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts2_hu5c8dc8009c93cbd020787dde3983cb07_297543_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts2_hu5c8dc8009c93cbd020787dde3983cb07_297543_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts2_hu5c8dc8009c93cbd020787dde3983cb07_297543_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/outskirts2_hu5c8dc8009c93cbd020787dde3983cb07_297543_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Osaka Castle Other Outskirts&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Other outskirts of the Osaka Castle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Renowned for it&amp;rsquo;s Winter Siege and Summer war battles that took place back in the Shogunate period of the 1610&amp;rsquo;s, when Japan wasn&amp;rsquo;t an united country, but rather a splintered region of battling shogunates, the castle also holds an important portion of history surrounding the second great unifier of Japan: &lt;strong&gt;Toyotomi Hideyoshi&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the outside I had to stand in a very long queue to access the castle, I was a bit impatient since I wanted to eat something and then head over to the Tsutenkaku, and coupled with my feet screaming at me to finally sit down, I made the mistake of buying the &lt;em&gt;Osaka Amazing Day Pass&lt;/em&gt; while standing on the line. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t smart at all since I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to fully take advantage of the other day pass attractions due to the little incident I will mention later in the article, but at least I was able to run straight into the day pass line and save me some precious time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested on visiting the castle, make sure you have very comfy shoes and your calves are strong, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of stairs ( the Castle has a total of 7 floors) so you will be going up and down a lot, it&amp;rsquo;s best to not rest a lot or else you will feel even more tired after you finally stand up, like me =).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;First floor 
    &lt;div id=&#34;first-floor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#first-floor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/samurai_hu1fe0c6c90ecbe2c037cb3c13f32aa37d_244460_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/samurai_hu1fe0c6c90ecbe2c037cb3c13f32aa37d_244460_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/samurai_hu1fe0c6c90ecbe2c037cb3c13f32aa37d_244460_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/samurai_hu1fe0c6c90ecbe2c037cb3c13f32aa37d_244460_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/samurai_hu1fe0c6c90ecbe2c037cb3c13f32aa37d_244460_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Samurai Equipment&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Samurai equipment found in Osaka Castle, from the Osaka Summer war period&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The castle&amp;rsquo;s first level holds famous Osaka&amp;rsquo;s samurai artifacts from the Edo period (If I recall correctly), there&amp;rsquo;s also something that caught my attention that I also noticed on my trip to Kyoto, about the Tiger rooms/Tiger drawings; basically there were no tigers in Japan back then, so how were artists able to draw tigers at all? You can find out the answer and more about this in my Kyoto article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/tiger_hu1ecc1cec68cb8e4ee398bb7b06882abb_162476_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/tiger_hu1ecc1cec68cb8e4ee398bb7b06882abb_162476_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/tiger_hu1ecc1cec68cb8e4ee398bb7b06882abb_162476_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/tiger_hu1ecc1cec68cb8e4ee398bb7b06882abb_162476_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/tiger_hu1ecc1cec68cb8e4ee398bb7b06882abb_162476_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Tigers&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tiger room drawings in Osaka Castle. note: Back then there were no tigers in Japan. Notice the distinct design in the eye area&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Second floor 
    &lt;div id=&#34;second-floor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#second-floor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second floor contains more exhibitions about sculptures and portraits in the castle. It explains how &lt;em&gt;Toyotomi Hideyoshi&lt;/em&gt; modeled the castle after the Azuchi Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Third floor 
    &lt;div id=&#34;third-floor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#third-floor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/portrait_huc6e9e57e91472d77c56cbbdf9f9483f1_233162_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/portrait_huc6e9e57e91472d77c56cbbdf9f9483f1_233162_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/portrait_huc6e9e57e91472d77c56cbbdf9f9483f1_233162_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/portrait_huc6e9e57e91472d77c56cbbdf9f9483f1_233162_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/portrait_huc6e9e57e91472d77c56cbbdf9f9483f1_233162_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Portrait&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Portrait of the Osaka Summer War / Winter Siege - The decisive battle that made the Tokugawa shogunate win the war. Every soldier is detailed and all generals of the war can be appreciated in this portrait, from both factions&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This floor contains some lovely portraits illustrating the famous Osaka Summer war and the Winter Siege. What I admired the most is the level of detail the painting goes into, thousands of soldiers, cavalry, artillery from each side, battle fiercely for controlling the Castle, a decisive victory was later awarded to the Tokugawa shogunate, sealing the fate of the Toyotomi clan and putting an end to the siege of Osaka. There&amp;rsquo;s an informative wall containing all sorts of details about each general of the battle, which is helpful for understanding more about each faction participating in the siege.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Fourth floor 
    &lt;div id=&#34;fourth-floor&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#fourth-floor&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fourth floor contains details concerning the great unifier Toyotomi Hideyoshi, all animated with tiny holograms. It&amp;rsquo;s a biography served in 19 funny displays&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Skipping all the way to THE ROOF 
    &lt;div id=&#34;skipping-all-the-way-to-the-roof&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#skipping-all-the-way-to-the-roof&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/roof_hubc12826456d22f3fe8282a023833eea4_1390350_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/roof_hubc12826456d22f3fe8282a023833eea4_1390350_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/roof_hubc12826456d22f3fe8282a023833eea4_1390350_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/roof_hubc12826456d22f3fe8282a023833eea4_1390350_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/roof_hubc12826456d22f3fe8282a023833eea4_1390350_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Roof view&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A view from Osaka&amp;rsquo;s castle roof to the North of Osaka.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  


I skipped all the way to the roof afterward. There&amp;rsquo;s an incredible view of Osaka from here, and it was completely worth it destroying my feet soles to feel the wind brace my entire body as I stared deep into the city and its mountains. My hair was pulling tricks on me with the wind and made me look like a maniac, and I wished there was a barber shop on the roof so that I observe the scenery more clearly, oh well..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The Incident 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-incident&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#the-incident&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember how I told you a little incident happened while I was visiting Osaka? Well, the incident was just me arriving at the hotel to take a shower before heading out to see &lt;em&gt;Tsutenkaku&lt;/em&gt; tower. I made mistake of showering with warm water and sitting in the tub relaxing for a good 40 minutes, I immediately felt tired and so I decided to lay over in my bed and browse the internet with my phone. Finally I decided to take a nap and I could&amp;rsquo;ve sworn I set the alarm to 40 minutes from now. It was 5pm and I closed my eyes. When I opened them again, it was 11PM, I wasted 5 hours sleeping and now I had little time any place, except for Osaka&amp;rsquo;s bar/night life district; &lt;strong&gt;Shinsaibashisuji&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Shinsaibashisuji 
    &lt;div id=&#34;shinsaibashisuji&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#shinsaibashisuji&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/boulevard_hu3266a63a0b5905801edde7166b7e24e0_256573_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/boulevard_hu3266a63a0b5905801edde7166b7e24e0_256573_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/boulevard_hu3266a63a0b5905801edde7166b7e24e0_256573_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-three/boulevard_hu3266a63a0b5905801edde7166b7e24e0_256573_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/boulevard_hu3266a63a0b5905801edde7166b7e24e0_256573_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Shinsaibashisuji boulevard&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Shinsaibashisuji boulevard view at night&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this district, you can find a lot of bars with various thematics. In all honesty, I&amp;rsquo;m remaining sober for the time being, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you&amp;rsquo;re barred from entering them, you can easily order tasty food (ramen, miso, and a lot of dishes which I have difficulty pronouncing, let alone typing into the article)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some interesting facts about this district: It has a latin american themed bar, &lt;a href=&#34;ghttps://www.google.com/maps/place/LUNA&amp;#43;SKY&amp;#43;International&amp;#43;Latin&amp;#43;Bar/@34.6744362,135.4995199,16z/data=!3m1!4b1!4m6!3m5!1s0x6000e7007c4c24b5:0xa2e55fb9faa857e8!8m2!3d34.6744318!4d135.5020948!16s%2Fg%2F11y2h6ztq1?entry=ttu&amp;amp;g_ep=EgoyMDI0MDkwNC4wIKXMDSoASAFQAw%3D%3D&#34;  &gt;
    LUNA SKY International Bar&lt;/a&gt;, so if you&amp;rsquo;re a fan of reggaeton and salsa or simply want to experience LATAM in Japan, this is the bar for you. There are also nightclubs and a lot of &amp;ldquo;servers&amp;rdquo; who will keep offering you a &amp;ldquo;night of fun&amp;rdquo; with their selection of girls. Do not pay attention to them and they will go away on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Youths can be observed walking on the boulevard, some are drunk, some are bold enough to say neutral stuff in front of you (I remember a girl there stared at me and said &lt;em&gt;Kokku-jin&lt;/em&gt; or something else which I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand immediately)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Onwards to Fukuoka 
    &lt;div id=&#34;onwards-to-fukuoka&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#onwards-to-fukuoka&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Osaka is a very dynamic, modern city, full of things and cultural wonders that make a great impact on the spectator. From it&amp;rsquo;s castles to its shrines, to its vibrant night life, I loved Osaka and so far consider it my favorite city, but sadly I need to leave to explore other places. I&amp;rsquo;ll move to the APA hotel right next to Gion station in Fukuoka, where I&amp;rsquo;ll explore several places such as the Fukuoka Zoo &amp;amp; Botanical Garden, the Wonder World Summer park, the Flower Museum in Uminonakamichi which I failed spectacularly to see, and the outskirts of Marine World. The blog entry is available &lt;a href=&#34;%22%22&#34;  &gt;
    here&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s it for today&amp;rsquo;s article, until next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-three/featured.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Trip: Kyoto visit, Nijo Castle, Kiyomizu-dera temple</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Kyoto 
    &lt;div id=&#34;kyoto&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#kyoto&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img2_huc50181285fe202d723797d196f09d160_152927_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img2_huc50181285fe202d723797d196f09d160_152927_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img2_huc50181285fe202d723797d196f09d160_152927_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img2_huc50181285fe202d723797d196f09d160_152927_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img2_huc50181285fe202d723797d196f09d160_152927_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Shinkyogoku boulevard&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A glimpse of Osaka&amp;rsquo;s nightlife in the Shinsaibashisuji district&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyoto holds a special place in my heart. It is Japan&amp;rsquo;s cultural capital, a place packed with millenia of history, and a place that gained the appreciation of the United States military upper echelons that helped it narrowly avoid nuclear destruction at the end of World War II, the same cannot be said about Hiroshima, the city that took its place and received the first atomic beating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kyoto was also the original capital of Japan for almost a thousand years. From 794 to 1868, when the Meiji Restoration occurred in the late 19th century, bringing all of Japan together once and for all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arriving at Kyoto from either Tokyo or Osaka is fairly easy, one only needs to take the corresponding local trains to a station that offers Shinkansen to Kyoto. In fact, from Osaka to Kyoto, you can take either the Hankyu Kyoto line, or the Tokaido-Sanyo line, both from the Shin Osaka Station.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Shinkyogoku Boulevard 
    &lt;div id=&#34;shinkyogoku-boulevard&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#shinkyogoku-boulevard&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apparently this is a famous boulevard in Kyoto and for a good reason, it holds a lot of antique/traditional stores that sell all sorts of items, from books and poems to traditional food and more modern comestibles. But the main reason I liked this boulevard is that it leads to another Buddhist temple and Swordsmanship museum that features katanas from the great Oda and his disciples. Particularly, I loved the explanation on how samurai swords were crafted. Sadly I couldn&amp;rsquo;t take any pictures from either place since pictures are restricted, but I can assure you it&amp;rsquo;s worthy to visit as a stop before Nijo Castle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img3_hu4fd37e106a78c3f4f70b7d84ee0402dc_263751_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img3_hu4fd37e106a78c3f4f70b7d84ee0402dc_263751_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img3_hu4fd37e106a78c3f4f70b7d84ee0402dc_263751_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img3_hu4fd37e106a78c3f4f70b7d84ee0402dc_263751_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img3_hu4fd37e106a78c3f4f70b7d84ee0402dc_263751_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Nijo Castle Outskirts&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Outskirts of the famous Nijo Castle&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Nijo Castle 
    &lt;div id=&#34;nijo-castle&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#nijo-castle&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some good 40 minutes of walking from Kyoto Shijakusho (you don&amp;rsquo;t need to walk that long, this was my mistake), Nijo&amp;rsquo;s castle entrance was just around the corner. The castle appears to be restored, but still I liked the aesthetic from the outside. To access Nijo Castle&amp;rsquo;s interior, you need to purchase a ticket in the entrance outside. It&amp;rsquo;s no more than $5 and it&amp;rsquo;s an amazing experience all around. You can walk around all interior rooms and find great explanations about each of them, such as the famous tiger rooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;About the Tiger Rooms 
    &lt;div id=&#34;about-the-tiger-rooms&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#about-the-tiger-rooms&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Something that caught my attention, were those rooms covered with paintings of the yellow stripped beasts with eerie eyes; Like a demon possessing the mammal, they stared at you with supernatural intensity and stood out as personal preferences from the painters portraying those giant cats. Well apparently the reason these tigers were painted so differently was due to the fact that Japan back then, didn&amp;rsquo;t have any tigers. Imagine trying to paint a penguin without never having seen one before except for its two wings, its beak and silhouette. Even if you were the world&amp;rsquo;s greatest painter, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be able to picture exactly the word penguin, so then you take some inspiration from the chunks of penguin bodies you were provided with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what happened with these tiger room paintings! Since the artists merely had the tiger hides and other products that came from the tiger, they took some creative liberties to bring the yellow felines into life. Quite interesting isn&amp;rsquo;t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img4_hu314065d13950540bf03502fd296a167e_24254_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img4_hu314065d13950540bf03502fd296a167e_24254_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img4_hu314065d13950540bf03502fd296a167e_24254_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img4_hu314065d13950540bf03502fd296a167e_24254_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img4_hu314065d13950540bf03502fd296a167e_24254_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Tiger Rooms&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Tiger drawings in rooms. Sadly this one is not the one I saw in Nijo castle. That one had more particular eyes along with a justification on the design. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to take pictures of it.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Kiyomizu-dera temple; A gruesome walk 
    &lt;div id=&#34;kiyomizu-dera-temple-a-gruesome-walk&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#kiyomizu-dera-temple-a-gruesome-walk&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img5_hu38351c42bcf941a8740d76df13fec0b7_76595_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img5_hu38351c42bcf941a8740d76df13fec0b7_76595_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img5_hu38351c42bcf941a8740d76df13fec0b7_76595_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img5_hu38351c42bcf941a8740d76df13fec0b7_76595_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img5_hu38351c42bcf941a8740d76df13fec0b7_76595_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;View of Kiyomizu-dera far away&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;View of Kiyomizu-dera from very far away. The inclined slope taxes your every fiber, so be prepared.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Mind work 
    &lt;div id=&#34;mind-work&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#mind-work&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mind works in mysterious ways, untamed and it will remain an anchor, drowning you. Taming it with persistence and determination however, and it will lead you towards your greatest achievements. I believe this is exactly what happened to me, when climbing to &lt;strong&gt;Kiyomizu-dera&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Japan&amp;rsquo;s love for walking 
    &lt;div id=&#34;japans-love-for-walking&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#japans-love-for-walking&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you ever find yourself in Japan, you will need to come to terms with it&amp;rsquo;s walking distances from one place to another. Renting a car might not be an option for most nationals (nor would I recommend it, it&amp;rsquo;s always a headache to take care of vehicles that aren&amp;rsquo;t yours) and sometimes the places you may want to visit are far away from the nearest station. This is exactly what happened to me when I was recommended a visit to &lt;em&gt;Kiyomizu-dera&lt;/em&gt;, by a very friendly local, in the ABC-Mart. Originally, I was going to return to Osaka with swollen feet and 5 kilos lighter, from all the sweat I poured over the streets of Kyoto, but, there was something calling me to visit this temple, in hopes of signing off my day in Kyoto, with a spiritual (mis)adventure, despite my legs screaming at me in agony.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;The Climb 
    &lt;div id=&#34;the-climb&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#the-climb&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Climbing the buddhist temple is no easy task. I had to depart from Kyoto&amp;rsquo;s ABC-Mart - walking - in direction to the monument, and was met with a barrage of &lt;em&gt;extreme-heat temperature&lt;/em&gt; alerts, a phenomenon that&amp;rsquo;s becoming far more frequent and deadly in Japan as Earth keeps suffocating. The view of the inclined slopes leading to the temple hit my soul with the power of a thousand waves. It&amp;rsquo;s not that I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to continue going, but felt like I couldn&amp;rsquo;t keep going forward. With every step, I felt as if the numbness of my feet crept higher into my body. It&amp;rsquo;s as if it was raining lead on that sunny day, for I felt my whole body heavy, about to fall into the sunset. Almost an hour of agony later, and I finally arrived at the gates of Kiyomizu-dera&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Entrance 
    &lt;div id=&#34;entrance&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#entrance&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img6_hu3cb513b7ee8879531beae679199898b9_193524_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img6_hu3cb513b7ee8879531beae679199898b9_193524_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img6_hu3cb513b7ee8879531beae679199898b9_193524_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img6_hu3cb513b7ee8879531beae679199898b9_193524_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img6_hu3cb513b7ee8879531beae679199898b9_193524_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;View of Kiyomizu-dera from the entrance&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;View of Kiyomizu-dera from its entrance&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tall, red, concave tiles adorned the roofs of the &lt;em&gt;pure water temple&lt;/em&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s the meaning of Kiyomizu-dera in Japanese. Thousands of tourists flooded the entrance, for a moment standing still looking at the wide lenses, the army of cameras immortalized their moments at the shrine in a snap moment. I had a smug grin all of a sudden as I realized my journey in Kyoto was coming to an end, as I headed inside the temple area looking for something. Something that I wasn&amp;rsquo;t even aware of, but it kept calling me, perhaps the Buddhist spirits called me inside to explore the elevated lands and its scenery?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img7_huf4fde8e202e6f99f31eed7f6c51fbe11_165255_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img7_huf4fde8e202e6f99f31eed7f6c51fbe11_165255_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img7_huf4fde8e202e6f99f31eed7f6c51fbe11_165255_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img7_huf4fde8e202e6f99f31eed7f6c51fbe11_165255_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img7_huf4fde8e202e6f99f31eed7f6c51fbe11_165255_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Shrine buildings&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the shrine buildings inside Kiyomizu-dera. They are really beautiful.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Water fountains 
    &lt;div id=&#34;water-fountains&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#water-fountains&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img8_hubab50cf6f629678d739b6d28955a7b1e_347701_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img8_hubab50cf6f629678d739b6d28955a7b1e_347701_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img8_hubab50cf6f629678d739b6d28955a7b1e_347701_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img8_hubab50cf6f629678d739b6d28955a7b1e_347701_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img8_hubab50cf6f629678d739b6d28955a7b1e_347701_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Otowo-no-taki fountains&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Otowo-no-taki water fountains&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stood amazed at the edge of the hill that gave a sincere view of Kyoto, being swallowed by the sunset, and hastily moved forward before the monks came out to close the temple. I walked all around and down some stairs in the green hills and found the famous blessed water cascade; &lt;em&gt;Otowo-no-taki&lt;/em&gt;, where there are three fountains of holy water, offers its guests the opportunity to take sacred water from one of its cascades. There&amp;rsquo;s a folklore that says drinking from any of these cascades, will bless the person with love, money and success. I sparkled some of it in my hands, specifically the central cascade&amp;rsquo;s water. I didn&amp;rsquo;t drink it though, so who knows if I ended up blessed, but I&amp;rsquo;m confident that it was the case =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Orange juice finale 
    &lt;div id=&#34;orange-juice-finale&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#orange-juice-finale&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I had explored all I could of the temple before it closed for the day, I was faced with a final hill to climb to head back to the exit. I&amp;rsquo;ll never forget the happiness I felt after experiencing this precious piece of Kyoto&amp;rsquo;s religious history. The red shrines now behind me, marked a new chapter in my life and made me reflect on a lot of experienced pains I believe, were self=inflicted. A feeling of bliss, knowing that my existence is not just wasting my already frail life force away, in a job I do not like, with limited to no learning, permeated my whole body. Despite my body shutting down on me and praying for a break, atop of this hill I saw myself, and so I took the last steps to receive my reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A tiny kiosk with two Japanese fellows, and a sea of fresh, ripe oranges was awaiting me. The slogan of this orange juice stand, I&amp;rsquo;ll carry for all my life, a golden slogan to all my struggles and challenges I&amp;rsquo;ve faced along the way. A nudge that can wake up even the biggest pessimist, from the bluest slumber. A slogan that shall unite all the globe and bring peace to humanity: &lt;em&gt;Life is too short, to say no to Orange juice.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img9_hud6e963cf76927e3a2274b10f247b534e_283003_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img9_hud6e963cf76927e3a2274b10f247b534e_283003_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img9_hud6e963cf76927e3a2274b10f247b534e_283003_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-two/img9_hud6e963cf76927e3a2274b10f247b534e_283003_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/img9_hud6e963cf76927e3a2274b10f247b534e_283003_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Orange juice&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Life is too short, to say no to Orange juice&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such tastiness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-two/featured.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Trip: Arrival at Haneda, tasty Teishoku, Shinjuku Express &amp; Toyoko Kids Epidemic</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img1_huc176263bef5d5380d7e71ff544c7ca52_154124_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img1_huc176263bef5d5380d7e71ff544c7ca52_154124_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img1_huc176263bef5d5380d7e71ff544c7ca52_154124_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img1_huc176263bef5d5380d7e71ff544c7ca52_154124_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/img1_huc176263bef5d5380d7e71ff544c7ca52_154124_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Nakano&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A view of Nakano&amp;rsquo;s Prefacture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Haneda&amp;rsquo;s Airport receives thousands of visitors every day, it&amp;rsquo;s size could subvert your expectations completely even if you&amp;rsquo;ve already done your fair share of travelling around the world. I was one of the many adventurers who witnessed the endless morning that followed us from Newark to Haneda&amp;rsquo;s airport for more than 14 hours. Due to timezones, if you leave in the morning from the US and fly through the Pacific, you&amp;rsquo;re likely to experience the eternal morning phenomenon - as I like to call it - in which the sun refuses to set even after arriving to the Asian Archipielago; I finally understand why this place is called &amp;ldquo;The Land of the Rising Sun&amp;rdquo; =)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On landing, travellers are expected to move from the gates to the arrivals section. As with other airports, there&amp;rsquo;s the possibility to connect flights and the signs hanging on the ceiling will let you know which path you should take in case you need to take another flight from the airport. Since this was my final destination, I followed the yellow billboard for domestic arrivals. Claiming checked bags can only happen once you&amp;rsquo;ve cleared customs and migration checks, which as expected from Japan, are strict and will not tolerate any illegal activites. You will also need to fill out some more japanese tax &amp;amp; immigration forms that luckily, are available online. From my experience, completing all forms in the official Japan Travel Web website, is way better than doing so by hand, as you can generate a QR code that immigration agents at the airport can scan to validate all your information. Afterwards, you will have to take your fingerprints and look straight towards the two cameras that will scan your face for security purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After these first two security levels, a final customs &amp;amp; clearance verification awaits you for completion before you&amp;rsquo;re free to exit. Depending on how you completed the immigration and clearance forms (electronically or paper), you will have to either verify your QR code in the electronic kiosk along with your passport, or you will need to fill out another paper form and proceed to the &amp;ldquo;PAPER&amp;rdquo; queues so that an airport officer can approve your stay in Japan. Since I went the digital route, verifying my information in the electronic kiosk and then walking towards the &amp;ldquo;ELECTRONIC&amp;rdquo; queue before finally exiting the airport. Quite confusing, isn&amp;rsquo;t it? Please make sure to know a little bit of Japanese or basic English at the very least in case you need help from the immigration officers. Be kind, patient and polite as you&amp;rsquo;re arriving as a guest and must respect the culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Stuff to do after exiting the airport 
    &lt;div id=&#34;stuff-to-do-after-exiting-the-airport&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#stuff-to-do-after-exiting-the-airport&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You should get yourself a prepaid train card (Pasmo or Suica) as soon as possible. Withdraw some Yen from the ATM, and move to your hotel/staying place. You can take the train (either JR Line, or local) and should be able to arrive to your destination shortly. There&amp;rsquo;s also Uber, taxi and other riding apps to commute via private transportation, and if you have a license (depending on your country of origin), you can rent a car and drive to your destination yourself. However these last two options are really unnecesary as Japan&amp;rsquo;s public transportation service is extremely good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Physical SIM Cards 
    &lt;div id=&#34;physical-sim-cards&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#physical-sim-cards&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be sure to get a SIM card ASAP. A pre-paid, physical SIM card works best, but I wanted to try eSIM for the first time in my life, so I can&amp;rsquo;t give a lot of detail on how to get a physical SIM card except for going to getting one of those outside the airport (If I recall correctly).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;eSIM 
    &lt;div id=&#34;esim&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#esim&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very easy to acquire electronic SIM cards (eSIM) in Japan. Personally, I used &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bmobile.ne.jp/english/esim.html&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    bmobile traveller eSIM&lt;/a&gt;, which I found very convenient, except for the fact that you will need to purchase this quite early in the morning afternoon in order to obtain access immediately. If you purchase your eSIM after 20:00, you will have to wait until the day after at ~11:00 tops for your eSIM to activate. Be sure to enter all your details correctly, otherwise bmobile will reject your eSIM and you will have to start the process from scratch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Teishoku 
    &lt;div id=&#34;teishoku&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#teishoku&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed for a day at Nakano, Tokyo, where I had the opportunity to visit a local restaurant that served &lt;em&gt;Teishoku&lt;/em&gt;. Teishoku are Japanese classical set meals that are served in a wide range of restaurants across Tokyo (I can&amp;rsquo;t talk about other regions but most likely there&amp;rsquo;s Teishoku there too, after all it&amp;rsquo;s still Japan).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img3_hu002c2401f4b541c5a8bc0a9bc3c379da_131041_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img3_hu002c2401f4b541c5a8bc0a9bc3c379da_131041_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img3_hu002c2401f4b541c5a8bc0a9bc3c379da_131041_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img3_hu002c2401f4b541c5a8bc0a9bc3c379da_131041_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/img3_hu002c2401f4b541c5a8bc0a9bc3c379da_131041_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Teishoku meal&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A Teishoku meal (not the one I&amp;rsquo;m eating in separate plates, the one containing pork)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Shinjuku Express trip, and the rise (and fall) of Toyoko kids 
    &lt;div id=&#34;shinjuku-express-trip-and-the-rise-and-fall-of-toyoko-kids&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#shinjuku-express-trip-and-the-rise-and-fall-of-toyoko-kids&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img13_huf67adcdd2183a4116a2a1c34ac8b1364_125860_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img13_huf67adcdd2183a4116a2a1c34ac8b1364_125860_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img13_huf67adcdd2183a4116a2a1c34ac8b1364_125860_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/img13_huf67adcdd2183a4116a2a1c34ac8b1364_125860_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/img13_huf67adcdd2183a4116a2a1c34ac8b1364_125860_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Toyoko kids laying on the street&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Toyoko kids laying on the street (I screwed up the picture, sorry.)&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an open space facing Toho Cinema in Shinjuku, a red zone that was once populated by vagabond children from near and distant lands. Today it serves as a reminder to the world, of the devastating consequences the pandemic brought back in 2019. Remnants of the original community of homeless kids that gathered around wearing clothes familiar from Japanese cartoons (anime) continue marking this place as one of the saddest in all of Tokyo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      &lt;img class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34; src=&#34;img16.jpeg&#34; alt=&#34;A view of Toho Cinema closed space&#34; /&gt;
      &lt;figcaption&gt;A view of Toho Cinema; The previously available space where the Toyoko kids used to hang out is now closed. Taken in September 2nd 2024&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Morbid Parallels 
    &lt;div id=&#34;morbid-parallels&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#morbid-parallels&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;ve heard about the infamous community of minors in Berlin back in the 80s who escaped home to live on the streets and worked in sex-work while binging on heroin, then you would know how depressing it is to watch the future generations free-fall without any support net to catch them. The kids of the Zoo Station (&lt;em&gt;Der Kinder vom Bahnhof Zoo&lt;/em&gt;) were notorious for coming from troubled home, and rapidly transforming into echoes of the heroin epidemic that slammed West Berlin in the mid-to-late 70s and propelled figures such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christiane_F.&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Christiane F&lt;/a&gt;. and &lt;a href=&#34;https://da.wikipedia.org/wiki/Babette_D%C3%B6ge&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    Babsi Döge&lt;/a&gt;, the latter being plastered in local Berlin&amp;rsquo;s newspapers as the youngest victim of the heroin epidemic sweeping away a generation in Germany. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Christiane_F._%5c%28film%5c%29&#34;   target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;
    A movie&lt;/a&gt; was also created back then documenting their gradual fall into addiction and their ultimate demise from heroin overdoses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/babsi_hud9c5d7d73ab89c7be7a01bf1dff60072_12988_330x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/babsi_hud9c5d7d73ab89c7be7a01bf1dff60072_12988_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/babsi_hud9c5d7d73ab89c7be7a01bf1dff60072_12988_1024x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-day-one/babsi_hud9c5d7d73ab89c7be7a01bf1dff60072_12988_1320x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/babsi_hud9c5d7d73ab89c7be7a01bf1dff60072_12988_660x0_resize_q75_box.jpeg&#34;
        alt=&#34;Babsi Doge&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;lsquo;Sie war erst 14&amp;rsquo; - Babsi Doge - The youngest recorded victim of the white dust plague in the Western European Nation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s currently happening in Japan is a strikingly similar situation to what happened at the Zoo Station in Berlin half a decade ago; Kids escaping from their homes, abandoning their abusing parents, pulling out their alcoholic drinks and cigarettes before proceeding to sell their bodies for quick cash. Its existence contradicts Japan&amp;rsquo;s strict image, challenging long-established dogmas and once again bringing out a dark chapter in the history of Nippon. Will this culture find a way to thrive and grow away from their self-destructive lifestyles? Or will a new &lt;em&gt;Bahnhof Zoo&lt;/em&gt; situation come to be and shake the core of Japan&amp;rsquo;s social assistance system, putting into light its terrible flaws that enable these youths to slip into the cracks? Only time will tell..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-day-one/featured.jpeg" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Japan Trip: Layover, NY, Do&#39;s &amp; Don&#39;ts</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-layover/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-layover/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;




  
  
    
  
  
    &lt;figure&gt;
      
      &lt;img
        class=&#34;my-0 rounded-md&#34;
        srcset=&#34;
        /posts/japan-trip-layover/image_hu33177afaf8fb1680ecbf37da7e2c3e72_25017_330x0_resize_box_3.png 330w,
        /posts/japan-trip-layover/image_hu33177afaf8fb1680ecbf37da7e2c3e72_25017_660x0_resize_box_3.png 660w,
        /posts/japan-trip-layover/image_hu33177afaf8fb1680ecbf37da7e2c3e72_25017_1024x0_resize_box_3.png 1024w,
        /posts/japan-trip-layover/image_hu33177afaf8fb1680ecbf37da7e2c3e72_25017_1320x0_resize_box_3.png 2x&#34;
        src=&#34;//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-layover/image_hu33177afaf8fb1680ecbf37da7e2c3e72_25017_660x0_resize_box_3.png&#34;
        alt=&#34;Japan&amp;amp;rsquo;s Imperial Navy Flag&#34;
      /&gt;
      
      &lt;figcaption&gt;Japan&amp;rsquo;s Imperial Navy Flag&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
  

&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Earlier this year I bought some plane tickets to visit a friend who lives in Japan. Well, being honest, there were other reasons for me to also take a shot and embark in such an ambitious journey. I&amp;rsquo;m coming off from a terrible three months or &amp;ldquo;babysitting&amp;rdquo; a legacy piece of software, and even as I write this I think &amp;ldquo;babysitting&amp;rdquo; is not the appropriate term, as you don&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;babysit&amp;rdquo; a sick person in hospice care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially I was going to spend my two weeks PTO home, after suffering some serious repercussions from my upset work/life balance, and coming to terms with white beard hairs and a lot of weight gain coupled with muscle loss. But I knew I&amp;rsquo;d regret it if I didn&amp;rsquo;t purchase those cheap tickets to Japan after three years of monitoring a bunch of flight itinerary search engines in order to escape from reality and recharge batteries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another reason for booking that flight was not just for Japan, but also for doing layover in the US and visiting some family relatives after more than a decade since our last reunion. It really teaches you a lot about loved ones not being eternal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;New York: 11 Years Later 
    &lt;div id=&#34;new-york-11-years-later&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#new-york-11-years-later&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can I say. I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a fan of New York, but the fact I have family there, was more than enough for me to consider putting aside my animosity towards this place, and doing a selfless act. Brooklyn had a lot of closed roads presumably due to labour day celebrations, but I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure. The place felt far more somber now and I credit this to the fact my visits a decade ago were fairly short, and I was always travelling there with other relatives, never alone. As always new yorkers are quite rude, at least my expectations there were fully met.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike other trips however, this time I did not stay in Manhattan, in a cozy hotel themed à la 1950s (as I fondly remember the Salisbury Hotel, now demolished and replaced by God knows what, I&amp;rsquo;ll find out about it in a future post); Exploring Central Park and visiting Times Square for the neophyte NYC experience, along with the museum, the statue of liberty and climbing the Empire State (I was never able to do that!!)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I stayed for roughly 6 hours at my grandma&amp;rsquo;s house, and that was entirely worth the whole trips price tag, and much more than that. She&amp;rsquo;s been living in Queens for quite a long time, and the place looks just as I remember it. It&amp;rsquo;s weird because this was the first time I did not take the dreaded subway to Queens, but from the distance I heard that monotone announcement voice from the metro station and it brought back a lot of phantoms from the memory palace, as we used to get lost and relied on physical maps to reach our final destinations (Google Maps and Waze weren&amp;rsquo;t that good back then, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t use prepaid cell phone plans)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Boeing Incompetence? 
    &lt;div id=&#34;boeing-incompetence&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#boeing-incompetence&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took a 4 hour nap and then went back to Newark and waited for boarding to my final destination. The initial wait was fine, the plane arrived on time, and the moment was perfect for me to shine (lovely rhyme); until the bad news echoed in the plane corridors, putting my annoyance in the pilot&amp;rsquo;s seat. Apparently our aircraft had some technical issues related to a plane carpet that was damaged before take off. How that came unnoticed during initial inspections after the plane arrived on time at Newark is beyond comprehensible for me. If this was a new aircraft (it wasn&amp;rsquo;t, I believe) then why did the plane carpets suddenly face issues? Was it due to a poor implementation, a poor design choice or merely a coincidence.. I guess I&amp;rsquo;ll never know, but since the latest news bringing to light some of Boeing&amp;rsquo;s quality issues, I&amp;rsquo;m more biased to this incident being more of a material issue and Boeing trying to cut corners with their equipment..&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 class=&#34;relative group&#34;&gt;Some Don&amp;rsquo;ts and Do&amp;rsquo;s 
    &lt;div id=&#34;some-donts-and-dos&#34; class=&#34;anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
    
    &lt;span
        class=&#34;absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 ltr:-left-6 rtl:-right-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a class=&#34;group-hover:text-primary-300 dark:group-hover:text-neutral-700&#34;
            style=&#34;text-decoration-line: none !important;&#34; href=&#34;#some-donts-and-dos&#34; aria-label=&#34;Anchor&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;        
    
&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO remain patient throughout this whole trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT pay for those stupid cabs. Just order Ride app instead, or you&amp;rsquo;re going to get ripped off&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO provide all documentation needed to the TSA officers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT pack your whole bag with a lot of snack bags; You&amp;rsquo;re not going to be able to pack much and it will be extremely annoying how your bagpack remains bloated, especially while on the plane&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO bring some snacks to your friends from abroad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT eat a lot before your next flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO take some anti nausea pills 30 minutes before your flight&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT throw up in the only restroom on the plane. I&amp;rsquo;m speaking from experience here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO kill some time watching movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT bring a lot of cash to your flights, its dangerous&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO be assertive and remain alert during your whole trip&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO NOT pick the aisle if you&amp;rsquo;re easily annoyed at some travellers going in-n-out constantly from their seats because they&amp;rsquo;re drunk or simply have a worm crawling up their butts, forcing them to stand up and move around the plane, as if they were taking dance lessons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DO take care of yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still 7 hours away from Tokyo, more updates will come very soon, I promise.=)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <media:content xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="//localhost:1314/posts/japan-trip-layover/featured.png" />
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No SICP Preparation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/no-sicp-preparation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/no-sicp-preparation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wanting to dive deeper into computer science concepts (maybe because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to be stuck just being a full stack dev forever), I went ahead and put my questionable foundations to the test, by returning to the acclaimed computer science book &lt;code&gt;Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs&lt;/code&gt;, by the reknowned authors Harry Abelson and Gerald Jay Sussman. Initially though, the book first caught my attention more than three years ago, but I excused myself from reading it out of pure Dunning Krugger instinct and not feeling the need to learn much more about computers, even though I work daily with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This blog is also a main motivator to pursue a better understanding of the concepts the authors presented, as part of the curriculum of computer science undergraduates at the Massachussets Institute of Technology (MIT). Not only because it will serve as a journal, but because it also gives me a sense of accountability, by having to actually sit down, read, not procrastinate and learn about the concepts shared in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I researched all across the web, and with the old shelved copy I possess of this book, I rapidly skimmed through the concepts. It was clear to me that the following were very important for throughly understanding what this book is about:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Algebra&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Pre-Calculus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; A basic knowledge of Scheme (a Lisp dialect)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Blog Post</title>
      <link>//localhost:1314/posts/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//localhost:1314/posts/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Originally I had created this blog to post content related to technology, but then, I wanted to expand this premise into just sharing my thoughts on several subjects, not necessarily limited to technology itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to reach out to me if you want me to investigate about a certain topic, related to the niche I&amp;rsquo;m pretending to post more about in this site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
